

ramiroandrade.com

hola@ramiroandrade.com +34 633 367 409 Barcelona, Spain

SUMMARY

I'm a Senior Product Designer who, for over a decade, has focused on designing impactful digital products and experiences, always with an eye toward simplifying the complex while ensuring top-tier usability and accessibility.

I also have front-end knowledge and a degree in marketing, two skills that work as an ideal complement and allow me to know and understand the entire design process, from research, context analysis, conceptualization, to solution and definition of metrics, in order to create more effective and goal-oriented solutions.

EXPERIENCE

November 2020 - Present

Senior Product Designer - IMMFLY

Revolutionizing in-flight digital products by crafting intuitive interfaces that enhance passenger engagement and satisfaction. I collaborate with developers and product managers to ensure a seamless integration of business requirements, technical constraints and user needs into best in class products for airlines such as British Airways, Iberia, Level and Vueling.

September 2012 - October 2020

Senior UX/UI Designer - Concreta

Started as UX/UI designer and evolved in the role. Throughout these years I designed, coded and managed noteworthy projects, creating all kinds of digital solutions that are used daily by thousands of users, from forms and mobile apps to self-service terminal's UI and complex design systems.

January 2011 - October 2020

Graphic and Web designer - Frelance

Over the years I've also worked as freelance as a graphic and web designer, helping brands and individuals find their new visual identity, launch cool apps and build eyecatching and intuitive websites.

EDUCATION

October 2019 - June 2020

Master in Digital Experiences Design - BAU Design College of Barcelona UX Research, UX/UI Design, Product Design, Agile, Lean UX and Front-end. GPA: 9.7

March 2009 - October 2018

Bachelor Degree in Advertising Communication - ORT University of Uruguay Communication Theory, Semiotics, Copywriting, Art Direction and Marketing. GPA: 82%

COMPLIMENTARY EDUCATION

- **Responsive Design** Course by Javier España How to design and code responsive sites.
- **Usability for Mobile Devices** Course by Daniel Mordecki Best practices for mobile design.
- Web Accessibility and WCAG 2.0 Course by Olga Carreras Fundamentals of web accessibility.

LANGUAGES

- Spanish Native
- English Professional
- Portuguese Basic

SKILLS AND TOOLS

Design

Figma, Design systems, Design thinking, Atomic design, Problem solving, Agile, Usability, Accessibility, UI design, UX design, User research, User testing

Front-end

HTML, CSS, SASS, Git, Visual Studio Code